In the midst of war, one man vanished into the jungle, and emerged as king.
Farewell to the King is a war, adventure film directed by John Milius.
An American soldier who escapes the execution of his comrades by Japanese soldiers in Borneo during WWII becomes the leader of a
personal empire among the headhunters in this war story told in the style of Joseph Conrad and Rudyard Kipling.
The American is reluctant to rejoin the fight against the Japanese on the urging of a British
commando team but conducts a war of vengeance when the Japanese attack his adopted people.
Learoyd, played by Nick Nolte.
Capt. Fairbourne, played by Nigel Havers.
Yoo, played by Marilyn Tokuda.
Sgt. Tenga, played by Frank McRae.
Gwai, played by Gerry Lopez.
Col. Ferguson, played by James Fox.
Farewell to the King is a 1989 American action adventure
drama film written and directed by John Milius.
It stars Nick Nolte, Nigel Havers, Frank McRae, and Gerry Lopez and is loosely
based on the 1969 novel Farewell to the King by Pierre Schoendoerffer.
Longtime Milius collaborator Basil Poledouris composed the musical score.
The film explores themes of guerrilla warfare,
paradise, island, shipwreck, desertion.